Register of the Oleg Ivanovich Pantiukhov papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Oleg Ivanovich Pantiukhov papers
1904-1992
82063
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 39 microfilm reels (6.6 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, reports, military documents, personnel lists, maps, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian participation in World War I, the Russian Revolution, and activities of His Majesty's 1st Rifle Household Troops Regiment during this period and subsequently in emigration.
Pantiukhov, Oleg Ivanovich, 1882-1974.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982. Incremental microfilm acquired in 2013.
Location of Original Materials
Microfilmed material originals are in private hands.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Collection(s)
Alex N. Kniazeff papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Mariia D. Vrangel' papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Boris I. Nedzvetskii papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Anatole S. Loukashkin papers, Hoover Institution Archives
R. V. Polchaninov papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Victor V. Alexeeff papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical/Historical Note
1882 March 25 (O.S.) Born, Kiev, Russia
1899 Graduated, Tiflisskii kadetskii korpus
1901 Graduated, Pavlovskoe voennoe uchilishche
1908 Married Nina Mikhailovna Dobrovol'skaia
1909 Organized first Russian Boy Scout unit
1915 Promoted to Colonel
1919 Elected Chief Russian Scout
1920 Emigrated to Turkey
1922 September 4 Moved to the United States
1929 Author, Russkim skautam: prikazy, instruktsii, informatsii i besiedy
1944 Nina Mikhailovna Pantiukhova died
1951 Moved to Nice, France
1969 Author, O dniakh bylykh
1973 October 25 Died, Nice, France
Scope and Content of Collection
Oleg Ivanovich Pantiukhov was a Colonel of the Imperial Russian Guard and the founder of the scouting movement in Russia in 1909. Most of the collection reflects these two aspects of his activities: a portion of the correspondence and some of Pantiukhov's writings and subject files deal with military matters: cadet corps, service in the guards and the life of Russian veterans in emigration.
An increment to the Pantiukhov papers was loaned to the Hoover Institution Archives in 2013. The increment was arranged in 27 boxes by Hoover staff, who then prepared this finding aid. All of the materials in the increment were subsequently microfilmed or digitized for the Hoover Institution. After the microfilm/digital copies were made, the original materials were returned to the donor.
The bulk of the collection is focused on the Russian scouting movement, from its formation and activities during the Russian civil war through its functioning as an émigré organization (or several organizations, as a result of splits). It appears that the country files were created or expanded by Pantiukhov's son, Oleg Olegovich Pantiukhov (who changed his name to John L. Bates in the United States): these cover primarily the interwar years and to a lesser degree the postwar years. Most of the postwar material on scouting is concentrated in correspondence with various scout leaders and active members. O. O. Pantiukhov kept up correspondence with his father's correspondents and continued to actively collect materials on Russian scouting abroad after his father's death: these activities are reflected in his own correspondence (in the Family file) and in the Russian scouting file. Nina Mikhailovna Pantiukhova was the head of the Russian Girl Guides and her papers (in the Family file) contain orders and correspondence that reflect her involvement.
Other collected materials on anticommunism and émigré activities may be found in the subject file.
The increment to the collection is organized into seven series: biographical file, family file, correspondence, speeches and writings, Russian scouting file, subject file, and oversize file.
Russia. Armiia. Leib-gvardii strelkovyi ego velichestva polk, 1.; Russia. Armii͡a--Officers.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; World War, 1914-1918--Russia.
- Correspondence, writings, reports, military documents, personnel lists, maps, printed matter, and photographs, 1904-1992 (Box 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Not yet described
- Biographical file, 1921-1986 and undated.; Box/Folder 1 (Reel 1)
  Awards, biographical sketches, business records, chronology, clippings, letters of recommendation, membership cards, receipts, subject file, miscellany, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Awards, 1950-1969 and undated; Box/Folder 1: 1 (Reel 1)
  - Biographical sketches, undated; Box/Folder 1: 2 (Reel 1)
  - Business records, 1921-1930.; Box/Folder 1: 3 (Reel 1)
    Includes correspondence, price lists, requests
  - Clippings, 1929-1986 and undated; Box/Folder 1: 4 (Reel 1)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1922-1929; Box/Folder 1: 5 (Reel 1)
  - Membership cards, 1958-1965; Box/Folder 1: 6 (Reel 1)
  - Receipts, 1922-1941; Box/Folder 1: 7 (Reel 1)
  - Subject file
    - Death and burial
      - General, 1973-1974.; Box/Folder 1: 8 (Reel 1)
        Includes clippings, correspondence, notes, obituaries, press releases, sketch of headstone
      - Letters of condolence, 1973-1974; Box/Folder 1: 9 (Reel 1)
      - Will, 1969-1973; Box/Folder 1: 10 (Reel 1)
    - Hundredth anniversary of birth, 1981-1984.; Box/Folder 1: 11 (Reel 1)
      Includes articles, clippings, correspondence, notes (in part, concerning the idea of a postage stamp honoring Pantiukhov)
    - Ninetieth birthday, 1972
      - General, 1972; Box/Folder 1: 12 (Reel 1)
        Includes clippings, notes, press releases and printed matter
      - Greetings, 1972; Box/Folder 1: 13 (Reel 2)
        Includes cards, letters, telegrams
  - Miscellany, undated.; Box/Folder 1: 14 (Reel 2)
    Includes lists, sketches of residence, tickets
- Family file, 1907-1992 and undated.; Box/Folder 2-3 (Reel 2-4)
  Artwork, biographical sketches, clippings, correspondence, and writings, arranged alphabetically by name of family member, and by physical form therein
  - Unidentified, 1907-1992
  - Cousin Edgar, Box/Folder 2: 1 (Reel 2)
  - Nieces and nephews (mainly German) correspondence, 1964-1965; Box/Folder 2: 2 (Reel 2)
  - Bates, John., 1948-1968
    See Pantiukhov, Oleg Olegovich
  - Bates, Hester (daughter-in-law) correspondence, 1968-1972 and undated; Box/Folder 2: 3 (Reel 2)
  - Bates, Mimi (granddaughter) correspondence, 1968-1972 and undated; Box/Folder 2: 4 (Reel 2)
  - Bates, Nina (granddaughter) correspondence with O. I. Pantiukhov, 1965-1967 and undated; Box/Folder 2: 5 (Reel 2)
  - Dobrovol'skii, Boris Mikhailovich (brother-in-law) correspondence, 1966-1970 and undated; Box/Folder 2: 6 (Reel 2)
  - Knorring, Ol'ga Nikolaevna (mother) correspondence, 1940-1968
    - Knorring, Nikolai Gustavovich, typed copy of a letter to her from her father, 1899-1900; Box/Folder 2: 7 (Reel 2)
    - Pantiukhov, Oleg Ivanovich, 1931-1936 and undated; Box/Folder 2: 8 (Reel 2)
  - Pantiukhov, Andrei Ivanovich (brother) death certificate, letters of recommendation and photograph, 1934; Box/Folder 2: 9 (Reel 2)
  - Pantiukhov, Igor' Olegovich (son) correspondence, 1938-1945; Box/Folder 2: 10 (Reel 2)
  - Pantiukhov, Ivan Ivanovich (father) typescript copy of selected diary entries for 1905-1910, Box/Folder 2: 11 (Reel 2)
  - Pantiukhov, Ivan Ivanovich (brother) correspondence, 1934-1941; Box/Folder 2: 12 (Reel 2)
  - Pantiukhov, Nikolai Ivanovich (brother) letter from, 1923; Box/Folder 2: 13 (Reel 2)
  - Pantiukhov, Oleg Olegovich (son) [also known as John L. Bates]
    - Clippings, 1958 and undated; Box/Folder 2: 14 (Reel 2)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1992
      - General, 1964-1988; Box/Folder 2: 15 (Reel 2)
      - Alekseev, Vasilii Ivanovich, 1985; Box/Folder 2: 16 (Reel 2)
      - Artem'ev, L., 1972; Box/Folder 2: 17 (Reel 2)
      - Boy Scouts World Bureau, 1966-1967; Box/Folder 2: 18 (Reel 2)
      - Danilevskii, Mikhail A., 1992; Box/Folder 2: 19 (Reel 2)
      - Donner, Nikolai Nikolaevich, undated, Box/Folder 2: 20 (Reel 2)
      - Eliseev, Fedor, 1972; Box/Folder 2: 21 (Reel 2)
      - Ermilov, Vladimir, 1969; Box/Folder 2: 22 (Reel 2)
      - Filatov, L. N., 1984-1986; Box/Folder 2: 23 (Reel 2)
      - Gardner, Ivan Alekseevich, 1974-1983; Box/Folder 2: 24 (Reel 2)
      - Gerich, Andrei, 1982; Box/Folder 2: 25 (Reel 2)
      - Gorokhovnikov, Nikolai Alekseevich, 1971-1972; Box/Folder 2: 26 (Reel 2)
      - Granberg, Vladimir, 1969-1974; Box/Folder 2: 27 (Reel 2)
      - Grigorovich-Barskii, L., 1982; Box/Folder 2: 28 (Reel 2)
      - Karachevskii-Karateev, Mikhail Dmitrievich, Prince, 1967; Box/Folder 2: 29 (Reel 2)
      - Kiselev, Aleksandr, Rev., 1973; Box/Folder 2: 30 (Reel 2)
      - Konovets, O., undated, Box/Folder 2: 31 (Reel 2)
      - Krasovskii, Vadim Vladimirovich, 1967-1984; Box/Folder 2: 32 (Reel 3)
      - Levitskaia, Marina, 1989; Box/Folder 2: 33 (Reel 3)
      - Levitskii, O. E., 1970-1972; Box/Folder 2: 34 (Reel 3)
      - Martinovich, Stepan Stepanovich, 1971; Box/Folder 2: 35 (Reel 3)
      - Mers'e, V., 1967-1970; Box/Folder 2: 36 (Reel 3)
      - Ob"edinenie kadet Nizhegorodskago grafa Arakcheeva kadetskago korpusa, 1981; Box/Folder 2: 37 (Reel 3)
      - Orekhov, Vasilii Vasil'evich, 1969-1972; Box/Folder 2: 38 (Reel 3)
      - Pantiukhov, Oleg Ivanovich, 1935-1973 and undated; Box/Folder 2: 39 (Reel 3)
      - Penkherzhevskii, A. 1972, Box/Folder 2: 40 (Reel 3)
      - Plekhanov, Mikhail Matveevich, 1971-1980; Box/Folder 2: 41 (Reel 3)
      - Polchaninov, Rostislav Vladimirovich, 1969-1984; Box/Folder 2: 42 (Reel 3)
      - Pozdieev, Konstantin Rostislavovich, 1971; Box/Folder 2: 43 (Reel 3)
      - Radetskii-Mikulich, Georgii Vasil'evich, 1972-1975 and undated; Box/Folder 2: 44 (Reel 3)
      - Rezaeva, Irina, 1971-1972; Box/Folder 2: 45 (Reel 3)
      - Sakhnovskii, Nikolai Ivanovich, 1968; Box/Folder 2: 46 (Reel 3)
      - Sedliarevich, Nikolai Mikhailovich, 1974; Box/Folder 2: 47 (Reel 3)
      - Selivanovskii, V. V., 1970; Box/Folder 2: 48 (Reel 3)
      - Shakhovskaia, Zinaida, 1982; Box/Folder 2: 49 (Reel 3)
      - Sikorsky, I. I., 1967; Box/Folder 2: 50 (Reel 3)
      - Solomonovskii, Igor' Konstantinovich, 1970-1972; Box/Folder 2: 51 (Reel 3)
      - Solov'ev, Aleksei, 1962-1986; Box/Folder 2: 52 (Reel 3)
      - Suchko, Vladimir Nikolaevich, 1972-1977; Box/Folder 2: 53 (Reel 3)
      - Tatarina, Vera, 1972; Box/Folder 3: 1 (Reel 3)
      - Temnomerov, Vladimir Apollonovich, 1972-1980; Box/Folder 3: 2 (Reel 3)
      - Tseder, R. Iu. 1958-1963 and undated, Box/Folder 3: 3 (Reel 3)
      - Urt'ev, Pavel Andreevich, 1972-1984; Box/Folder 3: 4 (Reel 3)
      - Vera Konstantinovna, Princess, 1972-1981; Box/Folder 3: 5 (Reel 3)
      - Viaz'mitinov, Aleksandr Mikhailovich, 1970-1974; Box/Folder 3: 6 (Reel 3)
      - Vrangel', Aleksei Petrovich, 1951; Box/Folder 3: 7 (Reel 3)
      - Zhukov, Romil Gavriilovich, 1970-1971; Box/Folder 3: 8 (Reel 3)
      - Zhukovskii, Anatolii, 1971-1984 and undated; Box/Folder 3: 9 (Reel 3)
    - Writings
      - "Istoriia russkikh skautov v Pol'she," photocopy of holograph, undated; Box/Folder 3: 10 (Reel 3)
      - "Russian Boy and Girl Scouts," typescript, undated; Box/Folder 3: 11 (Reel 3)
      - Untitled recollections of episodes of the Second World War, typescript, undated; Box/Folder 3: 12 (Reel 3)
  - Pantiukhova, Nataliia Evgenievna - Letter to, 1941; Box/Folder 3: 13 (Reel 3)
  - Pantiukhova (nee Dobrovol'skaia), Nina Mikhailovna (wife)
    - Artwork and illustrations, undated; Box/Folder 3: 14 (Reel 3)
    - Biographical sketches, undated
      - General. Includes a poem by A. Genkin dedicated to her, Box/Folder 3: 15 (Reel 3)
      - Tseder, R. Iu. [also known as R. Fekhner and R. Siedova]
        - Vospominania R. Iu. Fekhner o N. M. Pantiukhovoi," typescript, undated; Box/Folder 3: 16 (Reel 4)
          Includes two-page appendix entiled "Iz pis'ma R. Iu. Tseder o Rime i Florentsii"
        - "Tri podrugi," Vozrozhdenie, printed copy, Box/Folder 3: 17 (Reel 4)
    - Chronology of life, undated, Box/Folder 3: 18 (Reel 4)
    - Correspondence, 1907-1961 and undated
      - General, 1907-1942; Box/Folder 3: 19 (Reel 4)
      - Girl Guides Association (Robert Baden-Powell), 1927-1929; Box/Folder 3: 20 (Reel 4)
      - Pantiukhov, Oleg Ivanovich, 1929-1946; Box/Folder 3: 21 (Reel 4)
      - Pokrovskaia, Magdalina Nikolaevna, 1940-1961 and undated.; Box/Folder 3: 22 (Reel 4)
        Correspondence after 1944 is with O. I. Pantiukhov
    - Speeches and writings, 1929-1937 and undated
      - General, notes, undated; Box/Folder 3: 23 (Reel 4)
      - Untitled drafts of recollections covering 1891-1924, undated; Box/Folder 3: 24 (Reel 4)
      - Untitled notes on childhood, undated; Box/Folder 3: 25 (Reel 4)
      - "Zapiski Niny Mikhailovny Pantiukhovoi,", undated; Box/Folder 3: 26 (Reel 4)
      - Orders to Girl Guides, 1929-1937; Box/Folder 3: 27 (Reel 4)
    - Death file, obituaries and telegrams, 1944; Box/Folder 3: 28 (Reel 4)
    - Miscellany, including calling card and letterhead, undated; Box/Folder 3: 29 (Reel 4)
  - Pantiukhova, Ol'ga P. (sister-in-law) - Correspondence, 1935-1972; Box/Folder 3: 30 (Reel 4)
  - Ragozina, Mariia E. [Ragosin, Mary] (mother-in-law of O. O. Pantiukhov), 1943-1971 and undated
    - Correspondence with O. I. and O. O. Pantiukhov, 1943-1971; Box/Folder 3: 31 (Reel 4)
    - Writing. "Short Story of My Life," typescript, undated; Box/Folder 3: 32 (Reel 4)
- Correspondence, 1912-1973 and undated; Box/Folder 4-14 (Reel 5-23)
  Cards, letters and telegrams, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent and chronologically therein
  - General, 1922-1972
    - Incoming, 1922-1972 and undated.; Box/Folder 4: 1 (Reel 5)
      Mainly greeting cards
    - Outgoing
      - Undated, Box/Folder 4: 2 (Reel 5)
      - 1923-1927, Box/Folder 4: 3 (Reel 5)
      - 1928-1929, Box/Folder 4: 4 (Reel 6)
      - 1930, Box/Folder 5: 1 (Reel 7)
      - 1931-1933, Box/Folder 5: 2 (Reel 7)
      - 1934, Box/Folder 5: 3-4 (Reel 8)
      - 1935-1939, Box/Folder 5: 5 (Reel 8)
      - 1940-1947, Box/Folder 6: 1 (Reel 9)
      - 1950-1959, Box/Folder 6: 2 (Reel 9)
      - 1960-1964, Box/Folder 6: 3 (Reel 9)
      - 1965-1970, Box/Folder 6: 4 (Reel 9)
  - Unidentified, 1922-1972; Box/Folder 6: 5 (Reel 10)
  - Adam, Bishop, 1935; Box/Folder 6: 6 (Reel 10)
  - Adamovich, I., 1967; Box/Folder 6: 7 (Reel 10)
  - Agapov-Taganskii, 1922-1945; Box/Folder 6: 8 (Reel 10)
  - Alekseeva, M., 1957-1959; Box/Folder 6: 9 (Reel 10)
  - Amatov, Vasilii, Rev., 1936; Box/Folder 6: 10 (Reel 10)
  - Andreev, Iurii, 1935-1949; Box/Folder 6: 11 (Reel 10)
  - Andrei, Bishop, 1962-1972; Box/Folder 6: 12 (Reel 10)
  - Antonii, Archimandrite, 1923; Box/Folder 6: 13 (Reel 10)
  - Antonin, Archbishop, 1924-1938; Box/Folder 6: 14 (Reel 10)
  - Antonini, Eros de, 1930-1935; Box/Folder 6: 15 (Reel 10)
  - Apollonov, L. S., 1959-1967; Box/Folder 6: 16 (Reel 10)
  - Arbakh, Margarita, 1967; Box/Folder 6: 17 (Reel 10)
  - Arkhangel'skii, Aleksei Petrovich, 1939; Box/Folder 6: 18 (Reel 10)
  - Artem'ev, Leonid, 1949-1950; Box/Folder 6: 19 (Reel 10)
  - Arthur, J. M., 1922-1945; Box/Folder 6: 20 (Reel 10)
  - Asociacion de Boy Scouts de Chile, 1938-1941; Box/Folder 6: 21 (Reel 10)
  - Baiov, Aleksei Konstantinovich, 1927 and undated; Box/Folder 7: 1 (Reel 11)
  - Baldin, S., 1940-1941; Box/Folder 7: 2 (Reel 11)
  - Barachevskii, V., 1935-1962 and undated; Box/Folder 7: 3 (Reel 11)
  - Baranov, M. A., Rev., 1937-1938; Box/Folder 7: 4 (Reel 11)
  - Baumgarten, Sergei von, 1930; Box/Folder 7: 5 (Reel 11)
  - Bellin, V., 1958-1959; Box/Folder 7: 6 (Reel 11)
  - Benzeman, Gleb, 1965-1972; Box/Folder 7: 7 (Reel 11)
  - Berdiaeva, Faina Vasil'evna, 1960; Box/Folder 7: 8 (Reel 11)
  - Berg, Liudmila von, 1961-1969 and undated; Box/Folder 7: 9 (Reel 11)
  - Bezhinets, Georgii, 1935; Box/Folder 7: 10 (Reel 11)
  - Bezradetskaia, Ol'ga, 1950 and undated; Box/Folder 7: 11 (Reel 11)
  - Bil'derling, S., 1963; Box/Folder 7: 12 (Reel 11)
  - Bil'veiss, Mikhail, 1963-1972; Box/Folder 7: 13 (Reel 11)
  - Blazhovskii, Kirill N., 1948; Box/Folder 7: 14 (Reel 11)
  - Bobrinskii, Boris, Rev., 1969; Box/Folder 7: 15 (Reel 11)
  - Bobrovskii, Georgii A., 1946-1953; Box/Folder 7: 16 (Reel 11)
  - Bogdanovich, Pavel Nikolaevich, 1927; Box/Folder 7: 17 (Reel 11)
  - Bogdanovich, Vladislav L., 1933; Box/Folder 7: 18 (Reel 11)
  - Boiarskii, Vladislav, 1950; Box/Folder 7: 19 (Reel 11)
  - Bokach, Feodor, Rev., 1966; Box/Folder 7: 20 (Reel 11)
  - Bostrem, Ivan I., 1970-1973; Box/Folder 7: 21 (Reel 11)
  - Braun, Valentin V., 1959-1960; Box/Folder 7: 22 (Reel 11)
  - Brazol', Aleksandr, 1962-1972; Box/Folder 7: 23 (Reel 11)
  - Brazol', Boris, 1949; Box/Folder 7: 24 (Reel 11)
  - Bristol, Warren E., 1929-1934.; Box/Folder 7: 25 (Reel 11)
    See also Russian scouting file/ Welfare Committee for the Russian Boy Scouts Abroad
  - Bruns, Vladimir, 1926; Box/Folder 7: 26 (Reel 11)
  - Brusnikin, Igor', 1950; Box/Folder 7: 27 (Reel 11)
  - Budberg, Nikolai von, Baron, 1929-1969.; Box/Folder 7: 28 (Reel 11)
    Includes Budberg's biographical note on Col. D. D. Lebedev
  - Budberg, Roman von, Baron, 1967-1972.; Box/Folder 7: 29 (Reel 11)
    Includes Budberg's reminiscences
  - Bukanovskii, Aleksandr Evgen'evich, 1937; Box/Folder 7: 30 (Reel 11)
  - Bukharov, N. V., undated; Box/Folder 7: 31 (Reel 11)
  - Buliubash, Evgenii, 1962-1963; Box/Folder 7: 32 (Reel 11)
  - Cherednichenko-Mers'e, Pavel Vladimirovich, 1937; Box/Folder 7: 33 (Reel 11)
  - Chernavin, Vladimir Vasil'evich, 1937; Box/Folder 7: 34 (Reel 11)
  - Chernavina, Tat'iana, 1934; Box/Folder 7: 35 (Reel 11)
  - Cherskii, Georgii, 1965; Box/Folder 7: 36 (Reel 11)
  - Chubarov, A., 1929-1961; Box/Folder 7: 37 (Reel 11)
  - Dampel', E., 1923-1931; Box/Folder 7: 38 (Reel 11)
  - Daragan, Ivan Aleksandrovich, 1950-1959; Box/Folder 7: 39 (Reel 11)
  - Dementru (Dementroux), V., 1965; Box/Folder 7: 40 (Reel 11)
  - Derevitskii, A., 1930-1931; Box/Folder 7: 41 (Reel 11)
  - D'iakonov, Pavel Vasil'evich, 1972; Box/Folder 7: 42 (Reel 11)
  - Diakovskii, Vadim Mikhailovich, 1972; Box/Folder 7: 43 (Reel 11)
  - Disterlo, O., 1969 and undated; Box/Folder 7: 44 (Reel 11)
  - Domogatskii, Boris, 1968; Box/Folder 7: 45 (Reel 11)
  - Dorozhinskaia-Kurillo, S., 1970; Box/Folder 7: 46 (Reel 11)
  - Du Bellet, Henry P., 1970; Box/Folder 7: 47 (Reel 11)
  - Durlacher, Rimma Vasil'evna, 1972; Box/Folder 7: 48 (Reel 11)
  - Duvan (Duvano), 1959-1966 and undated; Box/Folder 7: 49 (Reel 11)
  - Dzhordzhadze, V., 1937; Box/Folder 7: 50 (Reel 11)
  - Dzhudzhiev, 1966; Box/Folder 7: 51 (Reel 11)
  - Dzhuliani, Aleksandr, 1927-1939 and undated; Box/Folder 7: 52 (Reel 11)
  - Efremov, A., 1946-1959; Box/Folder 7: 53 (Reel 11)
  - El'shin, A., 1941; Box/Folder 7: 54 (Reel 11)
  - Ern, N., 1946; Box/Folder 7: 55 (Reel 11)
  - Fedotoff-White, Dimitri, 1930-1931; Box/Folder 7: 56 (Reel 11)
  - Fekula, V., 1949; Box/Folder 7: 57 (Reel 11)
  - Fertov, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1964-1969; Box/Folder 7: 58 (Reel 11)
  - Filippov, Georgii Vladimirovich, 1937; Box/Folder 7: 59 (Reel 11)
  - Fisher, Ekaterina Sergeevna, 1966 and undated; Box/Folder 7: 60 (Reel 11)
  - Fomina, Tat'iana, 1966 and undated; Box/Folder 7: 61 (Reel 12)
  - Gagarin, Evgenii Nikolaevich, 1972; Box/Folder 7: 62 (Reel 12)
  - Gal'skoi, V., undated, Box/Folder 7: 63 (Reel 12)
  - Gardner, Ivan Alekseevich, 1967-1972 and undated; Box/Folder 7: 64 (Reel 12)
  - Gavrilov, Valentin Vasil'evich, 1952-1969; Box/Folder 7: 65 (Reel 12)
  - Geach, C. H., undated; Box/Folder 7: 66 (Reel 12)
  - Gegela-Shvili, S., 1967; Box/Folder 7: 67 (Reel 12)
  - Gerich, Andrei V., 1950; Box/Folder 7: 68 (Reel 12)
  - Geshvendt, Oleg, 1959; Box/Folder 7: 69 (Reel 12)
  - Gil'sher, G., 1935; Box/Folder 8: 1 (Reel 12)
  - Gillenshtein, 1959; Box/Folder 8: 2 (Reel 12)
  - Glavnyi Komitet Fonda Spaseniia Rodiny Imeni Velikago Kniazia Nikolaia Nikolaevicha, 1930-1934; Box/Folder 8: 3 (Reel 12)
  - Glazyrina, M., 1968; Box/Folder 8: 4 (Reel 12)
  - Glinka, Gleb Aleksandrovich, 1968; Box/Folder 8: 5 (Reel 12)
  - Golovanov, V., 1968; Box/Folder 8: 6 (Reel 12)
  - Golovchenko, O., 1960; Box/Folder 8: 7 (Reel 12)
  - Goncharov, Mikhail D., 1968; Box/Folder 8: 8 (Reel 12)
  - Gonetskii, Nikolai, 1967-1970; Box/Folder 8: 9 (Reel 12)
  - Gorbachevskii, V., 1949-1967 and undated; Box/Folder 8: 10 (Reel 12)
  - Gorbunov, A., 1960-1962; Box/Folder 8: 11 (Reel 12)
  - Gorchakov, G., 1930; Box/Folder 8: 12 (Reel 12)
  - Gorokhovnikov, N. A., 1961-1972 and undated; Box/Folder 8: 13 (Reel 12)
  - Granberg, Vladimir, 1935-1973; Box/Folder 8: 14 (Reel 12)
  - Gratsianskii, E., 1934-1935; Box/Folder 8: 15 (Reel 12)
  - Gratsianskii, N., 1960-1961; Box/Folder 8: 16 (Reel 12)
  - Grebenshchikov, Georgii D., 1928; Box/Folder 8: 17 (Reel 12)
  - Gniedich, Dimitrii Dimitrievich, 1935; Box/Folder 8: 18 (Reel 12)
  - Grenkhagen, N. E., 1962; Box/Folder 8: 19 (Reel 12)
  - Gubkin, M. V., 1954; Box/Folder 8: 20 (Reel 12)
  - Gubkina, 1965; Box/Folder 8: 21 (Reel 12)
  - Hubiak, Nicholas, Rev., 1941; Box/Folder 8: 22 (Reel 12)
  - Il'ina, M., 1965; Box/Folder 8: 23 (Reel 12)
  - Il'inskii, Andrei, 1950-1971; Box/Folder 8: 24 (Reel 12)
  - Ioann, Archbishop of Shanghai, 1965 and undated; Box/Folder 8: 25 (Reel 12)
  - Ionov, A., 1949; Box/Folder 8: 26 (Reel 12)
  - Ionov, Aleksei, Rev., 1972; Box/Folder 8: 27 (Reel 12)
    Includes photographs of Ipatieff and his son, Dmitrii, along with a brief text on Dmitrii's service and death in the First World War
  - Ipatieff, Vladimir N., 1939-1941.; Box/Folder 8: 28 (Reel 12)
  - Ipatii, Monk, 1969; Box/Folder 8: 29 (Reel 12)
  - Ivanov, Iurii, 1930-1935; Box/Folder 8: 30 (Reel 12)
  - Ivanova, Rita, 1954; Box/Folder 8: 31 (Reel 12)
  - Ivchenko, T., 1968; Box/Folder 8: 32 (Reel 12)
  - Izergin, I. V., 1968; Box/Folder 8: 33 (Reel 12)
  - Izrastsov, Konstantin, undated; Box/Folder 8: 34 (Reel 12)
  - Kambiadzhio, Iurii, 1955-1966; Box/Folder 8: 35 (Reel 12)
  - Kampe (Campe), Dagmara and Pavel, 1941-1961; Box/Folder 8: 36 (Reel 12)
  - Kanshina, Tat'iana Borisovna, 1967; Box/Folder 8: 37 (Reel 12)
  - Kantakuzina, O., 1971; Box/Folder 8: 38 (Reel 12)
  - Karrik, Valerii, 1929-1940.; Box/Folder 8: 39 (Reel 12)
    Includes his writings and bulletin "Sviaz'"
  - Karsakov, Pavel and Elena, 1912-1955 and undated
    - Incoming, 1921-1955 and undated; Box/Folder 8: 40 (Reel 13)
    - Outgoing, 1912-1936 and undated; Box/Folder 8: 41 (Reel 13)
  - Kazarinova, E., 1961-1972; Box/Folder 8: 42 (Reel 13)
  - Keizerov, Valentin Nikolaevich, 1947; Box/Folder 8: 43 (Reel 13)
  - Kek, Elena, 1968; Box/Folder 8: 44 (Reel 13)
  - Keller, Deane, 1929; Box/Folder 9: 1 (Reel 13)
  - Kharskii, Iosif, 1923; Box/Folder 9: 2 (Reel 13)
  - Khodnev, Dmitrii, 1967-1972; Box/Folder 9: 3 (Reel 13)
  - Khol'msen, Nikolai, undated; Box/Folder 9: 4 (Reel 13)
  - Khomentovskii, M., 1969; Box/Folder 9: 5 (Reel 13)
  - Khripunov, M., 1965; Box/Folder 9: 6 (Reel 13)
  - Kiselev, Aleksandr, 1946; Box/Folder 9: 7 (Reel 13)
  - Kniazev, Aleksei Nikolaevich, 1953-1972; Box/Folder 9: 8 (Reel 13)
  - Koiranskii, Genrikh Arnol'dovich, 1937-1969; Box/Folder 9: 9 (Reel 14)
  - Komarov, N. N., undated; Box/Folder 9: 10 (Reel 14)
  - Komarova, K., 1957; Box/Folder 9: 11 (Reel 14)
  - Konovets, A., 1973; Box/Folder 9: 12 (Reel 14)
  - Kornilova, V., 1923-1957; Box/Folder 9: 13 (Reel 14)
  - Korovnikov, M. D., 1972; Box/Folder 9: 14 (Reel 14)
  - Korvina, Z., undated; Box/Folder 9: 15 (Reel 14)